<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.camerondugan.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.camerondugan.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2021-04-10T11:00:33-04:00</updated><id>https://www.camerondugan.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle>This is my Jekyll website that is running Simple.css</subtitle><author><name>Cameron Dugan</name></author><entry><title type="html">My Crypto Adventures</title><link href="https://www.camerondugan.com/blog/crypto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Crypto Adventures" /><published>2021-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.camerondugan.com/blog/my-crypto-adventures</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.camerondugan.com/blog/crypto/">&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to my second ever blog post…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Background:
	I had saved up a bunch of crypto that I had mined in my free time over the course of about 10 or so months. Then I decided that I didn’t like having all of my money in bitcoin, so I decided to use a coin exchange to convert some of it to etherium. Enter: my mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had decided that I didn’t want to spend more than 1 USD to make the transaction, so I lowered the “fuel” on the transaction. Turns out, I had lowered it to the point where nobody would take the transaction. It took about a month before it became profitable to somebody to look at my transaction. All the while I wasn’t sure whether or not the exchange would just drop my request because of the time it was taking. Luckily, nothing bad happened and I have my crypto back in my wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really unpleasant looking at that 0 balance for a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways hope you enjoyed and have a wonderful day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cameron Dugan</name></author><summary type="html">Hello and welcome to my second ever blog post…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome To My Blog</title><link href="https://www.camerondugan.com/welcome/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome To My Blog" /><published>2021-03-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.camerondugan.com/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.camerondugan.com/welcome/">&lt;p&gt;I’m not entirely sure what I want this website to be, but for now it will mainly be a blog/links to various projects I’ve made or other’s projects that I really like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also try to add an RSS-Roll, hopefully it’ll be a landmine of good feeds that I subscribe to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try to keep formatting on this somewhat consistent, but I’m not making any promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current project I’m working on is currently called &lt;a href=&quot;https://thethe.dev&quot;&gt;Productivia&lt;/a&gt; but quickly switched to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Productivity&lt;/code&gt;. Hopefully this will end up bing a web/desktop/mobile based task system that levels out the workload you’ve been given to hopefully make your work less stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thethe.dev&quot;&gt;thethe.dev&lt;/a&gt; is still called Productivia because I’ve been too lazy to switch it back. Probably doesn’t matter too much because it’s going to be replaced with the finished product.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cameron Dugan</name></author><summary type="html">I’m not entirely sure what I want this website to be, but for now it will mainly be a blog/links to various projects I’ve made or other’s projects that I really like.</summary></entry></feed>